Amber Chiodini

(402) 516-4822 | amber.park@northwestern.edu | GitHub | LinkedIn | Chicago, IL

SUMMARY

Software developer with experience in both frontend and backend technologies. Working towards a Bachelor's in Biological Sciences and a certificate in full stack web development from Northwestern University. I have a strong interest in working in biotech, genomics, and precision medicine as I am passionate about building software that contributes to the field of biomedical research and treatment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Northwestern University | Chicago, IL

January 2020 - Present

Coding Bootcamp Student

- Group Project Eats & Beats
 - Worked with a team to create an application that brings a unique experience to users by retrieving new music and recipes using APIs.
- Group Project Keep on Giftin'
 - Worked with a team to create a full-stack application that reminds the user of certain dates to send friends and family gifts or cards.

Northwestern University | Chicago, IL

January 2020 - Present

Research Technologist 1

- Conducts daily health checks and feedings for zebrafish (Danio rerio).
- Maintains effectiveness and cleanliness of the aquatic housing systems by replacing filters and performing water quality tests.
- Communicates with researchers and supervisors via email or phone for animal health updates or mechanical discrepancies within the facility.
- Conducts a weekly census count for the Procurement, Receiving, and Census staff (PRC).
- Reviews and complies with all standard operating procedures and Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee guidelines pertaining to the fish facility.

Northwestern University | Chicago, IL

May 2019 – January 2020

Animal Care Technician 2

- Conducts daily health checks and feedings for zebrafish (*Danio rerio*).
- Maintains effectiveness and cleanliness of the aquatic housing systems by replacing filters and performing water quality tests.
- Communicates with researchers and supervisors via email or phone for animal health updates or mechanical discrepancies within the facility.
- Conducts a weekly census count for the Procurement, Receiving, and Census staff (PRC).
- Reviews and complies with all standard operating procedures and Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee guidelines pertaining to the fish facility.

EDUCATION

B.S. Northwestern University | Chicago, IL | Weinberg College Studying biological sciences.

In Progress

CERT Northwestern University | Chicago, IL | School of Professional Studies Learning full-stack web development.

In Progress

SKILLS

- HTML5/CSS3
- Bootstrap
- React.js
- JavaScript
- MySQL
- Command Line

- jQuery
- Express.js
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- Agile Methodology
- Git